# Abideen Olafimihan Frontend Developer

- ≥ olafimihana@gmail.com
- +2348024987319
- 79, Sokenu Road, Shomade's Compound, Oke Ijeun, Abeokuta, Ogun State.
- R Portfolio
- in LinkedIn
- Github

#### **Profile**

A ReactJS developer focused on building responsive cross-platform web applications. A team player committed to building user-friendly and lightweight web applications also concentrated on applying technical expertise to web development and was always determined to implement new strategies to make web apps more efficient.

# **Professional Experience**

#### 06/2023

## Abeokuta, Nigeria

# Complanet Technologies, Frontend Developer

- Collaborated with a team of two developers to build a popular betting organization grant application website (for both users and the admin website) and deployed it live. Which gives a platform for all agents of the betting company and any NGO bodies to apply for grants throughout Nigeria.
- Rebuilt a 1-year-old prototype Wordpress-powered NGO website for a client using the latest React practice.

#### 01/2023 - 06/2023

#### Lagos, Nigeria

## iobotech, Frontend Developer ☑

- Collaborated with a team of developers to build a modern and responsive company website.
- Collaborated to build a web app that enables customers to embrace predictive analytics and ensure effective building maintenance around the clock and from anywhere.
- Helped about 2000 customers to achieve a drastic reduction of about 50% in their operational costs and stricter security on their building maintenance.

#### 01/2022 - 02/2023

## Los Angeles, United State.

#### 100Devs, Frontend Developer

- Collaborated with a team of developers to build modern and responsive web applications using best practices.
- Applied agile methodologies like SCRUM for project management.
- Rebuilt a 4-year-old vanilla JavaScript-powered e-commerce website using React 18 and the React Context API for a better full-user experience.
- Rebuilt a 2-year-old prototype vanilla JavaScript-powered restaurant website using React 18, React Redux, and the Redux toolkit.
- Built an Amazon clone using React 18, React Redux, the Redux toolkit, and Firebase to manage the state of users.

# 01/2021 – present Abeokuta, Nigeria

## **Abitech**, Web Developer

- Created web applications and static websites for different clients across small and medium-sized businesses. I also consulted on SEO and social media strategy.
- Developed a fashion e-commerce app prototype.
- Gained excellent skills in using continuous integration tools.

#### **Projects**

#### 07/2023 – present

#### **GRANTIQ USER WEBAPP** 🗷

A platform where the agents of a popular betting company and NGO agencies can apply for grants for the development of Nigeria as a whole.

Stack: ReactJs, JavaScript, React Bootstrap, Axios and Lots more

07/2023 - present

#### GRANTIQ ADMIN WEBAPP

This helps the admin from the betting company keep track of all registered agents and NGOs, all grant applications submitted, and the status of the applications.

Stack: ReactJs, JavaScript, React Bootstrap, Axios and Lots more

05/2023 - present

#### Jumia Clone

This is a clone of a popular online store that allows effortless shopping, cart management, and a delightful user experience

Stack: React, JavaScript, Redux, ReduxToolKit, Tailwind CSS

# **Shoppy,** e-commerce website ☑

The website was built with ReactJS.

- learned how to manage the different states of an e-commerce website using the React Context API.
- learned how to pull product data from the Firebase Realtime Database.
- reinforced my knowledge of routing.

# freshAlways, e-commerce

The website was built with ReactJS.

- learned how to manage the different states of an e-commerce website using the React Redux and Redux toolkits.
- learned how to pull product data from the Firebase Realtime Database.
- learned how to work with Firebase storage and Firebase authentication.
- reinforced my knowledge of routing.

#### **Disney+ clone,** Movie Room ☑

The website was built with ReactJS.

- reinforced the knowledge of state management using React Redux and Redux toolkits.
- reinforced the knowledge of pulling data from the Firebase real-time database.
- learned how to provide a details page for all products using React-Router-Dom.
- reinforced my knowledge of routing.

## **Skills**

HTML Languages	• • • •	<b>CSS</b> Languages	• • • •
<b>JavaScript</b> Languages	• • • •	<b>React</b> Library	• • • • •
Redux Library	• • • •	<b>Tailwind CSS</b> Framework	••••
<b>Firebase</b> Database	• • • •	NextJS	• • • • •
Redux-toolkit	• • • • •		
Education			

10/2021 – 10/2022 Shrewsbury Shropshire, United Kingdom

## **University of Chester,** MSc. Biotechnology ☑

Graduated with a Merit (Top 5% of class).

09/2015 - 09/2019 Kwara, Nigeria

#### **University of Ilorin,** BSc Plant Biology

Graduated with First Class Honours (4.58/5.00, Top 0.1% of class).

Interests				
• Tourism.	• Reading books.	• Playing games.		
References				

Available on request